Guide to the Peter Duus Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Peter Duus papers
1966-2007
SC0916
Duus, Peter, 1933-
9.5 Linear feet
These papers consist primarily of course research materials, lecture notes, syllabi, handouts, and exams compiled by Duus from 1966-2007. Also included are materials from the Center for East Asian Studies, as well as biographical information about Duus.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Peter Duus is the William H. Bonsall Professor of Japanese History, Emeritus Stanford University; a Senior Fellow (by courtesy) at the Hoover Institution; and the Former Director of the Center for East Asian Studies at Stanford University. Born in Wilmington, Delaware in 1933, Duus earned an A.B. in History from Harvard College in 1955, his M.A. in Far Eastern Studies from the University of Michigan in 1959, and his Ph.D. in History from Harvard University in 1965. Duus held academic appointments at several institutions including Harvard and Washington University before joining the Stanford History Department in 1973, where he continues to teach and conduct his research.
Description of the Collection
These papers consist primarily of course research materials, lecture notes, syllabi, handouts, and exams compiled by Duus from 1966-2007. Also included are materials from the Center for East Asian Studies, as well as biographical information about Duus.
Access Terms
Duus, Peter, 1933-; Japan--History--Study and teaching.; Stanford University. Center for East Asian Studies.; Stanford University. Department of History.; Japan--History--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - The Rise of Modern Japan (II) [manuscript] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - World Outside the West (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History/Asian Languages/Humanities 92, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History/Asian Languages 92, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History/Humanities/Asian Languages 92, 1982-1983 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History/Humanities/Asian Languages 92, 1982-1983 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Asian Languages/History 91, 1977(folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Asian Languages/History 91, 1977(folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - History 92 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - History/Humanities/Asian Languages 93 (1), 1983-1984 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - History/Humanities/Asian Languages 93 (1), 1983-1984 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - History/Humanities/Asian Languages 93 (2), 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - History 292, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous notes and writings (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Meiji Culture (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - History 290A (1), 1988-1989 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - History 290A (1), 1988-1989 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 20th Century (1), 1996-1997 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 20th Century (1), 1996-1997 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 20th Century (2), 1996-1997 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 20th Century (2), 1996-1997 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - History 194B (1), 1983-1994 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - History 194B (1), 1983-1994 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - History 194B (2), undated (folder 1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - History 194B (2), undated (folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - History 194B (3), undated (folder 1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - History 194B (3), undated (folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - History 194B (4), undated (folder 1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - History 194B (4), undated (folder 2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - History 75 (U.S.-East Asia Relations), 1997-2001 (folder 1 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - History 75 (U.S.-East Asia Relations), 1997-2001 (folder 2 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - History 75 (U.S.-East Asia Relations), 1997-2001 (folder 3 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - History 75 (U.S.-East Asia Relations), 1997-2001 (folder 4 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - History 92B (East Asia in the Age of Imperialism), 2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - History 291/391 (Industrialization of Modern Japan), 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - History 275 (The Making of Imperial Japan), 1996 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - History 275 (The Making of Imperial Japan), 1996 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - World Outside the West, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Imperialism Research Materials (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - History 21 (World Outside the West), 1989-1991 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - History 21 (World Outside the West), 1989-1991 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - History 21 (World Outside the West), 1985-1986 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - History 21 (World Outside the West), 1985-1986 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - History 21 (World Outside the West), 1985-1986 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - English Language Research Material (Stanford/Hoover), circa 1990s (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - English Language Research Material (Stanford/Hoover), circa 1990s (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - History 407 (Pre-modern Japan/Washington University), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - History 407 (Pre-modern Japan/Washington University), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - History 407 (Pre-modern Japan/Washington University), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - History 205 (East Asia/Washington University), 1966 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - History 205 (East Asia/Washington University), 1966 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Eastern Civ. Syllabi (University of Arizona), 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Minyusha Historians (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous (including Stanford Overseas Seminar material), circa 2007 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - KCJS Alumni Directory, 1989-2004 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Japan Airlines Magazine, December 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - History 295 (Capitalism, Industries, and Social Conflict in Modern Japan) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - History 395 (Modern Japan Colloquium), 1974-1981 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - History 290 (The U.S. and Japan), 1982-1993 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - History 395B (Introduction, Perspectives on Tokugawa Japan) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - History 190 (Imperialism and the International Order in Modern East Asia), 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - History 194D (The Rise of Modern Japan), 1993-1998 (folder 1 of 4) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - History 194D (The Rise of Modern Japan), 1993-1998 (folder 2 of 4) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - History 194D (The Rise of Modern Japan), 1993-1998 (folder 3 of 4) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - History 194D (The Rise of Modern Japan), 1993-1998 (folder 4 of 4) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - History 395C-Xeroxed Articles (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - History 395C-Syllabi, 1980s-1990s (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - History 395C, 1998-1999 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - History 395C, 1998-1999 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - History 194D, 1997-2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bing Overseas Studies-OSPGEN 57, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Overseas Program-Accommodations, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Waseda, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - History 395C, 2002-2003 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - History 395C, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - History 194D, 1996-2001 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - History 194D [transparencies], circa 1990s (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - History 75 (The U.S. and East Asia), 1997-2001 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - History 395B, 1999-2001 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - History 395C, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - History 290 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - French Images of Asia (folder 1 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - French Images of Asia (folder 2 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - French Images of Asia (folder 3 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Kyoto Course (Postwar Japan), 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Japanese-Korean Relations (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Master Copies-Handout Material (History 91, 92, 93) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - History 194B Masters (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - History 194B Materials (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Xerox Materials (The East) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - History 290 Xerox (folder 1 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - History 290 Xerox (folder 2 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Colloquium (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Style Sheets (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Ph.D. Oral Regulations (East Asian Since 1600) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Kyoto Course (Industrialization in Three Societies), 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - History 194B Handouts (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - History 91-92, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Planning 91/92/93, 1979-1981 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Japan Foundation Grant Programs, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Syllabus-Rice Paddies (Harvard University), 1966-1970 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - History 91/92, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - History 91 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - History 92, 1979-1984 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - History 93, 1977-1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - HS 163 (The Chrysanthemum and the Yen), 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - History 194, 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - History 190-Syllabi and Materials, 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - History 194B (The Rise of Modern Japan), 1974-1987 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - History 194B (The Rise of Modern Japan), 1974-1987 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - History 293A (Power and Authority in Modern Japan: The 1930s), 1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - History 290 (Japan Since 1945: The Economic Miracle and Its Consequences), 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - History 294 (Imperialism in East Asia), 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - History 295 (Imperialism in East Asia, 1895-1950), 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - History 295 (Imperialism in East Asia, 1895-1950), circa 1984 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - History 395B (Tokugawa Japan), 1975 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - History 395C (Modern Japan), 1975-1988 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - History 495 (Graduate Seminar-Modern Japan), 1986 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - History 495 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - History 496 (Social Thought in Modern Japan), 1978-1980 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Summer Grant: Imperialism, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Association for Asian Studies Panel Project, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1980s-2000s (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Overseas Studies Program Committee/Kyoto Center, 1996-1997 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Center for East Asian Studies Steering Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Western Culture Task Force, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Japan Center (SJC-R) Program Review, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - International Studies Association (ISA)-Japan Association of International Relations (JAIR) Joint Convention in Japan, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - International Relations Program Review, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Overseas Studies Program Committee, 1995-1997 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - History Department Graduate Student Handbook, 1986, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Graduate Studies Committee (Mellon Grants), 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Handbook for History Majors, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - History Visiting Committee, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Center for East Asian Studies Steering Committee, 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - History Department Minutes, 1984-2003 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - History Department Minutes, 1984-2003 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Research Seminar (folder 1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Research Seminar (folder 2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Korea Trip, 1988-1989 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Korean Studies Program, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - East Asian History Ph.D. Qualifying Examinations Guidelines (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Center for East Asian Studies Steering Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Center for East Asian Studies (Title VI) Report, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Tamaki Foundation (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Institute for International Studies-Report to Provost on Asia Core Faculty, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Annual Faculty Reports, 1973-1999 (Box 16, Folder 11)